Emilia Williamson

Full Stack Developer

💡 Birmingham, UK 🌎 emiliawil 🔭 emiliawil.dev

Profile

A puzzle-addict since birth, nothing brings me more joy than tackling a tricky problem in a diverse group. As a former advice and guidance caseworker, my written and verbal communication skills have been invaluable as a team-oriented developer, and along with my technical proficiency and quick uptake of new skills, I'm now ready to hit the ground running in a professional tech team.

Skills

Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3

Design

UI, UX, User Stories, Low & High Fidelity Wireframing, Figma, Prototyping, Design **Thinking Process**

Project

Agile Methodology, Planning, Git & GitHub, DevOps, CI/CD, Pair Programming, Deployment

Frameworks and Tools

React, NextJS, Tailwind, PostgreSQL, REST, Express, Node, Postman, Eleventy

Testing

Test Driven Development, Jest, SuperTest, Cypress, React Testing Library

Interpersonal

Giving and receiving feedback, empathy, selfawareness.

Projects

Portfolio & Tech Blog 🛮

For my personal blog and portfolio, I knew I wanted to push myself and explore new technologies outside of those covered on my bootcamp. I really enjoyed using an SSG tool to manage my blog.

- Tech: JAMStack, Eleventy, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Nunjucks, Markdown
- Skills: Research, self-teaching, scaling a project, time-management, professional & technical writing, explaining complex topics

Insight Dashboard, School of Code one-week project

In our one-week project, my team decided to create a full-stack app that would encourage bootcampers to engage in active, creative and restful activities in their free time.

- Tech: JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Node, Express, REST API, React, HTML, CSS, Git, GitHub, Figma
- Skills: Pair programming, planning, strict time management, design process, conflict resolution, agile team-working, presenting

Dice Roller, Dice rolling app for tabletop RPGs ☑

This was a project for personal use. I chose to use the most vanilla approach possible, using no frameworks or extraneous tools, to keep my fundamentals sharp.

• Tech: Vanilla JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Professional Experience

Sep 2022 - present Remote

School of Code, Bootcamper

16-week intensive bootcamp in full stack JavaScript development.

- Developer mindset, creative problem-solving and agile methodologies, real-world projects
- Focus on PERN stack with exploration into different technologies
- Full web app workflow from ideation to deployment
- One-week and four-week projects presented to senior industry professionals

Jun 2017 - Sep 2022 Hednesford, UK

Rt Hon Amanda Milling MP / House of Commons, Caseworker

- Apolitical constituency-based worker managing a large caseload of 50+ new cases per week
- Managed email, telephone and walk-in enquiries
- Liaised and negotiated with Ministers, local authorities, schools, NHS organisations and Government departments
- Drafted press releases, social media posts, letters and emails
- · Assimilated complex information to relay to clients
- Interviewed and recruited new staff, took the lead on training

Sep 2015 – Feb 2017 Cannock, UK

Citizens Advice, Advisor & Gateway Assessor (Volunteer)

- Interviewed clients at walk-in appointments, built a quick rapport and explored their concerns
- Assisted clients in full appointments to assist with a wide range of issues, application forms and legal issues.

Education

Sep 2015 – Jul 2016 Birmingham, UK **Graduate Diploma in Law (Commendation),** University of Law Mooting, Business Challenge, Law Society Intervention Scheme

Sep 2012 – Jul 2015 Sheffield, UK BA Hons English (First Class), Sheffield Hallam University Class Representative (all 3 years), Creative Filmmakers Society, Archery Society, Final Project Mark: 85

Interests

Foreign Languages (I speak Basic Finnish and HSK-1 Mandarin. It's my goal to become a polyglot!)

Puzzles (I'm an avid puzzler - I've got about 50 issues of Beyond Sudoku on my bookshelf, and I'm currently tackling a notoriously difficult mystery from the 1930s called Cain's Jawbone where you have to arrange the book's pages to solve six murders.)

Knitting (A mindful but challenging exercise, and a rewarding way to express my creativity.)

Reading and Writing (As a literature graduate I've always been an avid reader. Lately I've been reading more non-fiction and maintaining my own tech blog at emiliawil.dev/blog)

Photography (I've done some freelance headshot photography in the past. I love the challenge of capturing someone's essence. As a people person, people are always my favourite subjects!)